#### Contact

Doha-Qatar +97455462457 (Mobile) sqatanani@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ mustafakatanani (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Hospitality
Revenue Analysis
Hotel Booking

### Languages

Russian (Elementary)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Arabic (Native or Bilingual)

### Honors-Awards

Agoda.com Gold Circle Award 2013
Communication Skills

# Mustafa Katanani

Product Development and Quality Control at Discover Qatar | FIFA | Sports Products | Stopover | Museums & Arts | Tours & Excursions Doha

# Summary

Responsible for soliciting and managing of revenue sales-related opportunities. Manages and provides training and work assignments. Actively up-sells each business opportunity to maximize revenue opportunity. Achieves personal and team related revenue goals. Responsible for driving customer loyalty by delivering service excellence throughout each customer experience. Provides service to our customers in order to grow share of the account on behalf of the company.

# Experience

Qatar Airways
Product Development and Quality Control
April 2021 - Present (5 months)

Kempinski Hotels Director Of Revenue Management November 2018 - March 2021 (2 years 5 months) Amman Governorate, Jordan

Pre-opening of the biggest convention centre in Amman city with more than 4000 SQM

Responsible of maximizing revenue for 278 rooms and RGI (Revenue Generation Index – measuring the hotel's position as compared to the competition) global sales revenue. Assisted the Management in determining budget and strategy. Also responsible for pricing strategy and for optimizing inventory.

Managing and directing E-Commerce.

- Contributed in devising the yearly budgets, per segment and per day, handling the cluster reservation team.
- Contributed in determining sales strategy Contributed in determining yearly rate tables for all market segments
- Prepared forecasts and chaired the Revenue meeting

- Determined and implements pricing strategies and circulates the recommendations
- Updated rates and restrictions throughout all distribution channels
- Produced bench-marking, GDS performance and other reports.
- Identifies new reservations sales business to achieve personal and property revenue goals.
- Understands the overall market, including competitors' strengths and weaknesses, economic trends, supply and demand etc. and knows how to sell against them.
- Closes the best opportunities for the property based on market conditions and property needs.
- Monitors same day selling procedures to maximize room revenue and control property occupancy.
- Gains understanding of the property's primary target customer and service expectations; serves the customer by understanding their business, business issues and concerns, to offer better business solution.

Daily Reservations Sales Activities

- Uses negotiating skills and creative selling abilities to close on business and negotiate contracts.
- Uses sales resources and administrative/support staff effectively.
- Assists in monitoring group reservation forecast data.

#### Freelance

Revenue Consultant January 2018 - October 2018 (10 months)

Jordan & Saudi Arabia

Managing the Revenue and E-commerce remotely for several properties;
Kempinski Hotel Amman
Grand East Hotel Dead Sea Jordan
Lacosta Hotel Aqaba Jordan
4 Lilly's Hotels & Apartments KSA

InterContinental Hotels Group (IHG®)
Director Of Revenue
October 2017 - December 2017 (3 months)
Dead Sea - Jordan

Crowne Plaza Resort & Spa Dead Sea 420 Rooms

Mövenpick Hotels & Resorts
Cluster Revenue Manager - Jordan
September 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 1 month)
Page 2 of 3

Jordan

Responsible of maximizing revenue for 5 Hotels & Resorts Total of 1220 rooms and RGI (Revenue Generation Index – measuring the hotel's position as compared to the competition) global sales revenue. Assisted the Director of Revenue Management in determining budget and strategy. Also responsible for pricing strategy and for optimizing inventory.

Wyndham Hotel Group
Cluster Revenue Manager
December 2015 - September 2016 (10 months)

Rebranding of Wintervalley Warwick Dead Sea into Ramada Resort and the opening of 3 Ramada Hotels & Resorts in Bahrain

Warwick International Hotels
Reservations Revenue Manager
March 2012 - December 2015 (3 years 10 months)

#### GRAND HOTEL KADRI

Front Desk Supervisor 2006 - 2008 (2 years)

FO & Reservation Supervisor

Milano Travel & Tourism
Tour Guide and Advisor
September 2005 - August 2006 (1 year)
Tour Leader from Amman - Jordan to Beirut - Lebanon
Trip advisor

Interval International
Sales Representative
January 2005 - August 2005 (8 months)

Time Share Interval International Program Sales

## Education

American University of Science and Technology Associate's degree, Management Information Systems, General · (2006 - 2008)